superprofs.com 2019-10-19

# SuperProfs

**Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 15-Nov-2017

All capitalized terms used and not otherwise defined herein shall have the meaning ascribed to them in SuperProfs’s Terms of Use.

SuperProfs.com, owned by Aurus Network Infotech Pvt. Ltd. (“SuperProfs”, We”, “Us”, or “Our”) respects Your rights regarding Your privacy and information, and We provide this Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) to help You understand how We collect, use, share, store and disclose information We obtain from or about You when You use the Services. This Privacy Policy applies to when You use Our Services.

As used herein the term “use” shall mean use, access, install, sign into, connect with, download, visit or browse the Services, as defined in the Terms of Use.

THIS IS A LEGALLY BINDING AGREEMENT BETWEEN YOU AND SUPERPROFS, AND BY USING THE SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS OF USE. You should review this Privacy Policy in conjunction with Our Terms of Use and any other agreement or policy provided by Us that governs Your use of the Services.

You should not use the Services if You do not agree with this Privacy Policy, Our Terms of Use and any other agreement or policy that governs Your use of the Services.

##  **1\. Information You Provide to Us Directly**

SuperProfs may collect different information from or about You depending on the manner in which You use the Services. The following examples are provided to help You better understand the information We may collect through Your use of the Services.

 **Please note, SuperProfs is not responsible for how others use information that is publicly available or otherwise accessible to others who have access to the Services.**

When You sign up for and use the Services (including through a Third Party Platform) We will collect any information You provide to Us directly such as the following:

###  **Registration Information:**

Information such as your e-mail address, password, Your date of birth, and age, and we will assign You a unique identifying number (“Registration Information”).

###  **Public Posting / Shared Content:**

Some of the Services may allow You to interact with other Users and/or post, share, communicate or otherwise transmit content publicly, such as by posting comments in the Q&A/ Discussion Forum, sending messages to others, or posting photos (collectively “Shared Content” or “Public Posting”). We may collect and store Public Postings and Shared Content. Shared Content or Public Postings may be publicly available or viewable by others depending on where such content is posted.

You hereby grant SuperProfs a non-exclusive right and license to reproduce, distribute, publicly perform, offer, market and otherwise use and exploit the Public Postings and Shared Content.

###  **Course Information:**

We collect information relating to taking Courses, including, interchanges with the Professor, teaching assistants and other Students, answers to questions and other items submitted to satisfy the Course requirements, (“Course Information”).

You hereby consent to Our sharing of Registration Information and Course Information to Professors and teaching assistants. SuperProfs does not control how Professors or teaching assistants treat Registration Information or Course Information and is not liable for Professors’ or teaching assistants’ use of such information.

###  **Payment Information:**

We may collect certain information regarding Your purchase (such as Your name and zip code) as necessary to process Your order. You will be required to provide certain payment and billing information directly to our payment processing partners, including but not limited to Your name, credit card information, billing address and zip code. We do not access, store or collect Your credit card information.

###  **Information Received Through Your Third Party Platform:**

The Services may contain third party links or allow You to access the Services through Third Party Platforms, such as Facebook. If You use Our Services on or through a Third Party Platform, including via any mobile and/or other Internet connected devices (“Wireless Devices”), or click on third party links, the collection, use, and disclosure of Your information and Your use of the Services will also be subject to the privacy policies and other terms of such third parties or Third Party Platforms. You should review such privacy policies, terms, and other agreements.

When You use Our Services through a Third Party Platform, You allow Us to collect and use certain information from Your Third Party Platform profile or account as permitted by the terms of that Third Party Platform and Your privacy settings and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **By way of example only** , We may collect some or all of the following information from Your Third Party Platform account when You register or use the Services on or through a Third Party Platform:

  * Your full name
  * Your profile picture or its URL
  * Your ID Number, which is linked to publicly available information such as Your name and profile photo
  * The login e-mail address
  * Your physical location and that of Your access devices, including any Wireless Device
  * Your gender
  * Your birthday
  * List of friends or contacts

You may choose not to allow the Third Party Platform to provide Us with certain information about You, but You might not be able to use certain features of Our Services if You enable such restrictions.

###  **Communications, Support Requests, Potential Abuse:**

If You contact Us for assistance, or to report a problem, concern, potential abuse or other issues regarding the Services, including before You have created an Account, We may collect and store Your contact information, communication, and/or other information about You, including but not limited to Your name, e-mail address, location, operating system, IP address, any other information You provide Us in the course of such communications, and/or other information that may be collected by automated means described herein. We reserve the right to conduct further research and obtain further information as necessary. We will use the information to respond to You and research Your request/communication, all in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

##  **2\. Information We Collect Through Automated Means**

###  **Technical and Usage Data**

When You access the Services, including browsing Our Courses, We may collect certain information by automated means. This information may include without limitation: (a) technical information about Your computer or Wireless Device, such as Your IP address, device type, operating system type and version, unique device ID, browser, browser language, domain and other systems information, platform types (collectively, “Technical Information”); and (b) usage statistics about Your interaction with the Services, including Courses accessed, time spent on pages or the Services, pages visited, search queries, click data, portions of the Services used, date and time, and other information regarding Your use of the Services (collectively, “Usage Data”).

This Technical Information and Usage Data, which may be linked to Your information, is collected through the use of server log files and tracking technologies, including: (i) cookies, which are small files that websites send to Your computer or Wireless Device to uniquely identify Your browser or mobile device or to store information in Your browser setting; and (ii) web beacons, which are small objects that allow Us to measure the actions of visitors using the Services. For more detailed information regarding how We use cookies and other technology, please review the additional information in this Privacy Policy under the Section entitled “Our Cookies Policy”.

Geolocation Information: IP addresses received from Your browser or device may be used to determine Your approximate location, such as the city, state and/or country associated with an IP address.

##  **3\. Cookies and Data Collection Tools**

Like many websites and app providers, SuperProfs (and/or service providers acting on Our behalf, such as Google Analytics and/or our third party advertisers) may use server log files and automated data collection tools, such as cookies, tags, scripts, device and web beacons (collectively, “Data Collection Tools”) when You access and use our Services. In some cases, We tie the information gathered by these means to Our other information You provide and that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy. These Data Collection Tools automatically track and collect certain Technical Information and Usage Data that Your browser sends when You use our Services. In some cases, We will associate this Technical Information and Usage Data with other information about You.

Cookies are small text files placed onto your computer or device as you browse the Internet. Cookies can be used to collect, store and share bits of information about your activities across websites and services, including on SuperProfs. They also allow us to remember things about your visit to SuperProfs, such as your preferred language and other choices/settings and generally make the site easier for you to use.

We use cookies for a variety of reasons, including to: (i) analyze the usage of our Services; (ii) provide a more personalized experience; (iii) allow You to more easily login to use our Services; and (iv) help make Your use of Our Services more efficient and more valuable by providing You with a customized experience and recognizing You when You return.

We may also employ web beacons or other technology for a variety of reasons such as: (i) allowing Us to know if a certain page was visited or whether an e-mail was opened; (ii) allowing Us to advertise more efficiently by excluding our current Users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new installation.

You can set Your web browser to warn You about attempts to place cookies on Your computer, limit the types of cookies You allow or refuse cookies altogether; however, You may not be able to use some or all of the features of the Services, or Your experience will be different or less functional if You refuse/disable cookies.

Third parties with whom We partner to provide certain features on Our site may use Local Storage Objects, also known as Flash Cookies (LSOs) to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing LSOs.

By using Our Services, You consent to Our use of cookies, web beacons, LSOs and other Data Collection Tools as described in this Privacy Policy.

##  **4\. Online Advertising**

We may use third-party advertising technologies that allow for the delivery of advertising about our Services on other websites You visit and other applications You use. The ads may be based on various factors such as the content of the page You are visiting, information You enter such as Your age and gender, Your searches, demographic data, user-generated content, and other information we collect from You. These ads may be based on Your current activity or Your activity over time and across other websites and online services and may be tailored to Your interests.

We use third parties to help deliver these tailored advertising on other websites and in mobile applications. These third parties may place cookies or other tracking technologies on Your computer, mobile phone, or other device to collect information about Your use of the Services as discussed above and may access these cookies or other tracking technologies on Your computer, mobile phone, or other device You use to access the Services in order to serve these tailored advertisement. We also may share with third-party advertisers a hashed version of Your email address that is anonymized and cannot be used to identify you, solely in non-human readable form and content that You share publicly when using the services (e.g, user-generated content) for purposes of delivering tailored advertising.

We neither have access to, nor does this Policy govern, the use of cookies or other tracking technologies that may be placed on Your computer, mobile phone, or other device You use to access the Services by non-affiliated, third-party ad technology, ad servers, ad networks or any other non-affiliated third parties. Those parties that use these technologies may offer You a way to opt out of such ad targeting.

When using a mobile application you may also receive tailored in-application advertisements. Each operating system, iOS for Apple phones, Android for Android devices and Windows for Microsoft devices provides its own instructions on how to prevent the delivery of tailored in-application advertisements. You may review the support materials and/or the privacy settings for the respective operating systems in order to opt-out of tailored in-application advertisements. For any other devices and/or operating systems, please visit the privacy settings for the applicable device or contact the applicable platform operator.

Please note that to the extent advertising technology is integrated into the Services, You may still receive advertisements on other websites and mobile applications even if You opt-out. In that case, the advertising will not be tailored to Your interests. Also, we do not control any of the above opt-out links or whether any particular company chooses to participate in these opt-out programs. We are not responsible for any choices You make using these mechanisms or the continued availability or accuracy of these mechanisms.

##  **5\. Our Policy Concerning Children**

We recognize the privacy interests of children and We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under the age of 13 should not use or attempt to use Our Services. If We learn that We have collected personal information (as defined by applicable law) from a child under 13, We will take reasonable steps to delete such information.

Parents who believe that SuperProfs might have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 may submit a request to [support@superprofs.com](mailto:support@superprofs.com) and request that the information be removed.

##  **6\. How We Use the Information We Collect**

SuperProfs may use the information We collect through Your use of the Services to:

  * Provide, administer, and facilitate Your use of the Services, including to display customized content;
  * Process or fulfill Your request(s) and/or order(s) for Courses, products, services, information or features;
  * Communicate with You concerning Your Account by:
    * Responding to Your questions or concerns;
    * Sending You Service and administrative messages and information, including comments from Professor or teaching assistants, those about changes to the Service, and updates to our Terms of Use, and Privacy Policy;
    * Emailing You information or providing in app messages about Your progress in Courses, new services, new features, promotions, newsletters, and other available Courses, which You can opt out of at any time;
    * Sending push notifications to Your Wireless device to provide updates and other relevant messages.
  * Understand and improve the Services and develop new products, services or features;
  * Enable User-to- User communication and interaction;
  * Manage Your Account preferences, establish Your Profile and Registration Information;
  * Facilitate the technical functioning of the Services, including without limitation to troubleshoot and resolve issues, secure the Services; and prevent fraud and abuse
  * Respond to customer support questions and issues and resolve disputes;
  * Create, review, analyze and share Technical Information;
  * Analyze trends and User traffic, track purchases and usage information;
  * Advertise our Services on third party websites or mobile applications
  * Market, process or fulfill Promotions administered or sponsored by SuperProfs;
  * Solicit feedback from Users;
  * As required or permitted by law;
  * As We, in Our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary or required to ensure the safety and/or integrity of Our Users, employees, third parties, members of the public, and/or our Services;
  * Identify unique users across devices; or
  * Tailor advertisements across devices.

##  **7\. When and How We May Share/Disclose Your Information with Third Parties**

We will share Your information which may include Registration Information and Shared Content and Course Information, with the following third parties or under the following circumstances or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

###  **About You with the Professor:**

We may share Course Information, course, assignment, and quiz completion activity, and certain Registration Information and Profile Information with Professors or teaching assistants of the Courses in which You enroll or for which You request information.

###  **Third Party Business Partners, Service Providers, Contractors or Agents**

We may share Your information with third party companies that perform services on Our behalf, including for payment processing, order fulfillment, data analysis, marketing services, advertising services (including but not limited to retargeted advertising), e-mail and hosting services, and customer services and support. These third party service providers may access Your personal information, and are required to use it solely as directed by Us for the purpose of Our requested service.

We may also share Your information with third party companies that we partner with to provide certain services to You in connection with the Services. Those partners’ collection and use of information is subject to their privacy policies and other terms. You should review such privacy policies, terms, and other agreements.

###  **About You with other Users**

As mentioned above some of your Registration Information (for. Eg. Your name) may be publicly viewable, including to other Users. In addition, if you ask a question to a Professor or Teaching Assistant, information about you, such as your name, may be publicly viewable by other Users.

###  **Business Transfers, Sales, Mergers, or Divestitures**

In the event that SuperProfs undergoes a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture or dissolution, or a sale of all or a portion of its assets, We may share, disclose or transfer all of Your information to the successor organization in such transition or during steps in contemplation of such activities (e.g., due diligence).

###  **With Your Permission**

We may share information with Your consent to third parties not within scope of this Privacy Policy.

###  **Aggregate or De-identified Information**

We may disclose or use aggregate or de-identified information for any purpose.

###  **Promotions**

We may share Your information in connection with any Promotion You enter on or through the Services, as necessary to administer, market, sponsor, or fulfill the Promotion or as required by applicable laws, rules or regulations (for example, to provide winners’ lists or make required filings as appropriate) or in accordance with the applicable rules of the Promotion. We may share Your information with a third party assisting us in administering the Promotion.

###  **Social Media Features**

Our Services may include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. Our integration of these features may allow third party social media provided to collect certain information such as Your IP address, which page You are visiting when using Our Services, and to set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly through the use of Our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

###  **Safety, Security, Cooperation with Law Enforcement, & Compliance with Legal Obligations**

We may disclose Your information to third parties, if We, in our sole discretion, have a good faith belief that disclosure is: (1) permitted or required by law; (2) requested in connection with or relevant to a judicial, governmental or legal inquiry, investigation, order, or proceeding; (3) reasonably necessary to enforce Our Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy, or any other legal agreements; (4) required to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, abuse, misuse, potential violations of law (or rule/regulation), and/or security or technical issues; or (5) required or reasonably necessary in Our discretion to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of SuperProfs, Our Users, employees, members of the public and/or our Services. We may also disclose information about You to Our auditors or legal advisors in conjunction with accessing Our disclosure obligations and/or rights under this Policy.

##  **8\. How Do We Keep Your Information Secure?**

SuperProfs takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to, or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of, data that You share and We collect and store. These measures vary based on the sensitivity of the data we collect and store. Unfortunately, however, no system can be 100% secured, and We cannot guarantee that communications between You and SuperProfs, the Services, or any information provided to Us in connection with the information We collect through the Services will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of User information at any time. Your password is an important component of Our security system. As such, it is Your responsibility to protect it. Do not share Your password with any third parties. If Your password has been compromised for any reason, You should change it immediately and contact [support@superprofs.com](mailto:support@superprofs.com) with any concerns.

##  **9\. Your Choices Regarding the Use of Your Information**

You can always choose not to provide certain information to Us but You may not be able to use certain features of the Services. If You do not wish to receive promotional communications from Us, You can opt-out by: (i) following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the promotional communication You receive; or (ii) managing Your e-mail preferences by signing into Your Account, clicking on the Account Settings link under the Your Profile button in the site header, and navigating to the Notifications tab.

Please note that despite Your opt-out choice or indicated email preferences, We will still send You transactional and/or relationship messages regarding the Services, including, for example order confirmation, important updates regarding the Services, and notices regarding our policies.

The browser You use may provide You with the ability to control cookies or other types of local data storage. Your Wireless Device may provide You with choices around how and whether location or other data is collected and shared. SuperProfs does not control these choices, or default settings, which are offered by makers of Your browser or mobile device operating system.

You may also have other choices as described in the Advertising of Third Party Products/Services section.

If You have any questions about Your information, our use of this information, or Your rights when it comes to any of the foregoing, contact us at [support@superprofs.com](mailto:support@superprofs.com).

##  **10\. How to Access & Update Your Information and How to Delete Your Account and what Happens when Your Account is Terminated or Deleted**

Should You require any assistance on the above, You may also contact Us via email at [support@Superprofs.com](mailto:support@Superprofs.com).

###  **Account Terminated or Deleted**

Please be aware that even after Your Account is terminated or deleted some or all of Your information may still remain visible to others, including but not limited to any information that has been: (a) incorporated into others User’s content, comments, postings, submissions, including but not limited to Course comments ; (b) copied, stored or disseminated by other Users; (c) shared or disseminated by You or others such as in a Public Posting; or (4) posted on a Third Party Platform. Termination of Your Account will not result in the removal of information collected and already put in aggregate form or information that cannot, in Our sole discretion, be removed without undue burden to SuperProfs. SuperProfs is not able and/or obligated to remove any of Your information from a Third Party Platform.

Even after You delete Your Account or Your Account is terminated, we may retain Your information as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so and in accordance with applicable law. In addition, Your information may not be deleted from servers of the Third Party Platform You use to access Our Services. We may retain backup copies of Your information on Our servers or databases (and/or any authorized third party servers or databases We use) for legitimate purposes such as assist with any legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce Our agreements. Such information may be disclosed pursuant to this Privacy Policy regardless of whether Your Account is deleted or terminated.

##  **11\. Modifications to this Privacy Policy**

From time to time, We may update this Privacy Policy. Modifications will become effective on the day they are posted unless stated otherwise.

As permitted by applicable law, if You continue to use the Services, after the effective date of any change, then such access and/or use will be deemed an acceptance of and an agreement to follow and be bound by the Privacy Policy as changed. The revised Privacy Policy supersedes all previous Privacy Policies. For this reason, We encourage You to review this Privacy Policy any time You use the Services. Upon Our request, You agree to accept or sign a non-electronic version of this Privacy Policy and any other policies or agreements set forth or available through any Third Party Platform.

  12.  **Grievance officer**

In accordance with Information Technology Act 2000 and rules made thereunder, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below:

Mr. Ajay Singh,

Aurus Network Infotech Pvt. Ltd.., North Star Business Centres, B 109, Sec 5, Noida-201301, UP, India.

Email: ajay.singh@superprofs.com  
Time: Mon – Fri (11:00 – 18:00)
